What the hell are you doing?!
There's no need for you to die.
I can't.
He told me to kill myself if I lost.
It hurts.
I'd rather be dead.
Anything but the punishment!
Why isn't the hero coming?
What?
Someone told me.
They said that when I was in the depths of despair,
a hero would come to save me.
Those words have lingered in my ears ever since.
Get her some treatment.
Right!
I don't need my payout.
Let's go.
Still, that was amazing!
I came to respect you all over again.
Your backup was plenty impressive, too.
No, no, not at all.
To be honest, I barely did anything.
You know, I really wish you'd start
recognizing your own talent.
Maybe I should pick this up as a hobby?
Huh? Pick it up?
Yeah, I was pretty good, right?
Considering it was my first time playing and all.
Worms, the both of you.
Erna, lemme pick your brains.
What's the play here?
We need to fall back for now.
The door we came in through is blocked,
so we'll have to find another exit.
Fighting in here puts us at too big a disadvantage.
True that.
One question, though.
Yeep?
Where is the exit?
How unlucky.
Well, them's the breaks.
MISSION: Dreamspeaker III
Hey, Barron.
Oui?
It's pretty obvious you coulda
kept workin' as a boxer.
Why dirty your hands with this spy killer shit?
Oui, I see no reason to tell you.
Fair enough.
Incoming, from the right?
Fuck off!
You're not layin' one goddamn finger on her!
You actually fell for it?
What a child.
Big Sis Sybilla!
You're finished.
Nah...
Check out what I just nicked.
You wretch...
All right! Let's get the hell outta here!
Yeep!
Me wo aketa kikkake wa
I would expect no less out of a spy from the Republic.
Kokoro saku joukei
The problem is...
you made too big of a scene.
Hirari hirari yubi no sukima kara
You gotta keep a closer eye on your valuables, man.
Mietekuru shinjitsu wo nirame
Ohh!
Hey, I remember you!
Kizukareta no wa, rakuen?
And on top of that, you revealed too many of your tricks.
Massakasama ochite
I knew you specialized in picking pockets.
It was obvious my lighter was
Aa tatoe kouya demo
the first thing you would go for.
And when you spotted the floor plan,
Hitori de ikiru to oritachimashou
you would have no reason not to follow it.
The map contained the location of the stairs
leading to the fifth floor.
If you turn at the fire extinguisher
and pass through the kitchenette,
Koko ni aru hana wa ima eien nare to
the emergency exit will be right in front of you.
Gokujou no chihedo wo haite watashi ga ueta mono
But that emergency exit
is precisely where I laid my trap!
Get back here!
Kono koe de ashi de te de watashi no mama mogaku hodo ni
Yeah, that's not happenin'!
Exactly, I have you right where I want you.
Doushiyou mo nai sekai ga itoshii
Yeep?
Nah, this ain't right.
What?!
Tadoritsuku wa kanarazu
Musekaeru hodo no yume
That should be enough fire
to fight for a good three minutes.
But why?
Once the fire runs out,
you'll be plunged back into darkness.
Running is for cowards, and that shit ain't me.
I don't need this gun, either.
You're talking about cowardice in a fight to the death?
Y'know, is it just me, or is that pain I see in your eyes?
Aren't we supposed to be the ones
who're backed into a corner?
What happened to you?
Why're you doin' this?
Shut up!
Become my Worker Ant and kill spies for me.
You're dead!
I'll kill you, and I'll save my family!
Family, huh?
I feel ya.
I wanted to save my siblings, too.
Then why are you smiling?!
Outta regret!
I was drowning in despair,
and I thought I had no future.
But here's the thing.
There was this guy who called me "magnificent."
Nowadays, I'm a god-damned optimist.
Keep on killing.
And if you lose, end your life
if you want your family to survive.
Then you and your optimism can die here and now!
Perish!
How unlucky...
My gun?
You and your sticky fingers.
I thought you said guns were cowardly.
What?
Who cares about being cowardly
in a spy fight to the death?
That was a lie I told to get you to lower your guard.
I was fibbin'.
Then, why?!
Why not just take the emergency exit and flee?
Oh, I get it.
There's a set of stairs behind that door.
You set a trap there or somethin'?
Damn, you really were on edge.
You'd have to be, to miss something so obvious.
I missed something?
You can't be serious!
Look, man, Mouzaian's a tough language.
Learnin' to speak it was as far as I got.
I can't read a lick of it.
I had no idea the map said "emergency exit" on it,
so I was just runnin' around at random.
If you lose, end your life...
I'm sorry, I wasn't able to save you.
A hero is coming.
They'll save you when you fall
into the depths of despair.
You mustn't die before they get here.
There is no hero.
The hell's up with this guy?
He didn't even try to stop the bleeding.
Oh, goddamnit!
Is it morning already?
We make a damn good tag team, you and me.
I feel like I can do anything
when I'm with you, Big Sis Sybilla.
"Big Sis," huh?
All righty! Leave it all to your big sis!
You're hurt.
We should have that back-alley doctor
Teach found examine you.
Yeah, let's get me patched up.
That's incredible.
The two duos both took out their opponents.
Just as expected.
They lived up to all my hopes.
No, that's not all.
You predicted this would happen
and stationed the Specialist squad
for maximum effect.
I thought Monika was the only one on Lamplight
whose skills were on a different level,
but I can see I was wrong.
I am worried about Lily, though.
We should send the others in to back her up.
Ex-exactly what I was thinking.
Yo, it's me!
Annette?!
What's going on?
I'll make it brief!
Me and Flower Garden ended up
getting chased around town by the cops.
But we managed to give them the slip!
Oh, that's good, sounds like you two
managed to overcome your crisis, too.
That was when twelve assassins came after us, yo.
Twelve?!
Hold on!
You're safe, right?
Where's Lily?
She drew them away from me,
and now she's buying time.
We'll send the others over at once!
No, see, what Flower Garden
wanted me to tell you
was that the same thing might be
happening to the others.
Those are SOS calls from Sybilla and Monika.
If there are actually twelve assassins
going after each location...
...then just how many people are we up against?
Thirty? Forty?
Or worst of all, could there be as many as fifty of them?
Two hundred and eighty-seven...
That's how many Worker Ants
I have operating in Mitario.
When they find spies, they kill them.
And if they fail, another twelve
come in to finish the job.
Those are their marching orders.
The fact of the matter is,
you and your allies simply got overrun.
The CIM's Retias team got wiped out.
I'm told the five of them were able to
take out fourteen Worker Ants,
but that was as far as they got.
The Goosefoot Sisters were smarter.
They ran for it after their seventh kill.
The older sister didn't make it, but still.
Shadowseed committed suicide after nine kills.
The JJJ tried to come after me too,
but they quieted down right quick
when I sent the Giraffe and the Turtle
back to them in bodybags.
Now Ouka, Ouka was something else.
He took out seventeen Worker Ants all on his own.
Seeing his corpse gave me quite a shock.
I had no idea he was just a teenager.
It won't take me long to replace the killed Ants, either.
All I have to do is snatch up promising civilians
and torture them, after all.
Just...
Just how many lives do you intend on ruining?
Don't talk back to your king.
Oh, dear!
Young Klaus doesn't seem to be coming, does he?
Well, that's fine.
Time to kill the hostage.
That's your femoral artery I just shot.
You probably have about five minutes
before you bleed out.
Wouldn't you say it's about time?
Don't you want to tell me your name before you die?
MISSION: Dreamspeaker III
They showed up out of nowhere.
Who are they?
Are there seriously twelve of them?
I got it open.
T-tell me...
You'd be able to escape
if you were on your own, right?
Don't worry about me and just-
If I did, it'd make a certain someone real sad.
Bottom line is, ditching you isn't an option.
Someone's here.
Yeep...
Don't you worry.
I made myself a promise.
Nobody who calls me their big sis
is dyin' on my watch!
Annette's probably gotten word to the others by now.
All I gotta do is stall them a bit longer.
As Lamplight's leader,
it's time for me to put my life on the line.
I'm Lily, master of buying time.
Don’t you dare count me out!
Who are these people we're up against?
I'll disguise myself as the boss.
If our opponents are working with the Empire,
they should know what he looks like.
If Monika and I work together,
we should be able to break their line.
But what about Lily and the Sybilla duo?
We have the boss.
Hold on!
The math doesn't add up.
There are three different locations that need backup!
Thea...
We have to do what we can with what we have.
Grete!
How can you be so brave?
I don't have your ingenuity.
I don't have the nerve to dive into
life-threatening situations.
What is it I can do?
I'm not that strong.
All I have is a desire to repay the boss.
It's a dependence bordering on obsession.
I want to do right by the man
who returned my affection,
even after my love was unrequited.
Please, read back over the reports
and think about what it is you can do to help.
I believe in you.
Ms. Hearth, what can I even do?
Why did you put so much confidence
in someone like me?
You'll be the strongest spy around.
But you can't just be any old spy.
I want you to become a hero
who saves your enemies, too.
It made me so happy when you said that.
The future seemed so rosy.
I was going to join Inferno someday
and work by your side.
But the truth is I'm powerless.
I'm an incompetent commander
and a failure of a spy.
I wish I could just disappear!
I wish I could just fade away and die!
Hey, Sis!
I don't want you to die, yo.
Annette?
I had a lot of fun last month,
when you did all that stuff for me.
I gotta say, I was surprised.
I was like, she's so meddlesome,
and she never actually accomplishes anything,
and all she's good for is picking up guys.
You don't mince your words, do you?
But even so, I don't hate you.
Y'know, Flower Garden made a request.
She wanted me to pass you a message, yo.
She did?
From what she found,
there's been a rumor going around Mitario.
The story goes that when people
fall into the depths of despair,
a hero will show up to save them.
A hero?
That reminds me...
Monika's report said something similar.
About how Purple Ant's minions believe in a hero.
Sybilla said the same thing,
that her opponent was muttering about a hero.
What's going on?
Where's the rumor coming from?
Someone working for Purple Ant?
Apparently, they say the the hero is
a beautiful girl with black hair.
This next bit is from Flower Garden.
Pretty convenient, huh?
Now, go piggyback off the rumor
and become a hero for real!
That's the end of her message.
Now, I gotta get back and help her out.
A hero?
With black hair?
What does it all mean?
I have to do what I can.
I figured it was about time.
What's the matter?
I don't bite.
You want me to save you, right?
Sure, I'll help out.
I've started getting a soft spot for you lot.
I'm being serious.
So come on, let me out already.
Your little party trick isn't going to work on me.
I knew it.
I'm powerless.
There's nothing I can do.
Oh, I get it.
You made a major blunder recently, didn't you?
Well, that makes two of us.
I blew it, big time.
You did?
Don't you remember?
You're talking to the guy who went after Bonfire
and got his ass handed to him.
I even spouted off those embarassing lines
about us becoming rivals.
You want to hear my story?
Don't worry, it won't take long.
I used to be a pretty boring guy.
My parents told me to take over the family business,
and I spent my days doing what they expected of me.
But that all changed when I met this
weird guy called Purple Ant.
Purple Ant...
He remolded me into a spy.
My talents surpassed those of
the other Worker Ants in no time,
and he gave me all kinds of special treatment.
I traveled around the world,
murdering one politician and spy after another.
But it turned out...
that all that awaited me was tedium.
You get it, right?
There was no goal behind my killing.
I just was carrying out
Purple Ant's orders, nothing more.
All I was doing was taking the people
the conveyer belt sent me
and slapping an "assassinated" stamp on them.
There was this big old void in my heart.
What was I even living for?
I see...
But then, someone told me a secret.
They did?
Yeah...
They told me that there was
someone who could fill that void,
a monster who was stronger than anyone,
who no one could kill,
and who could complete any mission.
I thought that the monster would be able
to give my life meaning,
but look at where that got me.
Let me guess, your blunder left your heart in pieces,
and you have no idea
how to get your life back on track.
That ringing any bells?
We should team up.
As fellow losers, we can retake our lives together.
Your offer doesn't make sense.
If what you said is true,
then you shouldn't be able to defy Purple Ant.
Oh, please, don't lump me in with the cannon fodder.
His control over me isn't as strong.
Do you have any proof of that?
I didn't kill myself, did I?
The other Worker Ants all try to off themselves
as soon as they lose.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Now, it's time to make your choice.
Are you going to let me out, or leave me here?
By the way, the part about me being special was true.
Purple Ant didn't order me to kill myself if I lost.
He ordered me to decieve my enemies
and make it back no matter what it took.
You're not too bright, are you?
Fooling you took barely any effort at all.
He never fails to impress.
Not only did he escape all on his own,
he even captured a hostile.
What frightening amounts of talent he has.
Are you Purple Ant?
I see my reputation precedes me.
Now, how about you and I have a little chat?
Aa, kataashi de tatte tsurai okimochi
Mou kyouyuu shite chanto yottemasuka?
Ai o motte chigau nanika abiserare
Yakkaisou de jama na watashi, waita waita
Honto daijoubu?
Sore kiite dou suru no?
Tada homeru dake de ii
Iienai ienai kagami no sei
Mirenai kienai yogoreta sei
Assari kamikitte sameta me de uso o minuku
Katenai kaenai na muku na hin
Suteru mono nai mukurodashi
Kakugo wa kakusazu hada de te ni motte aragau
(whoo, whoo, ooh)
Rakugaki darake no aimai na unmei
Kami de sae keisotsu ni damashiteku